Hey everyone and welcome! Get ready because today we are firing up an amazing machine for an adventure
みなさん、こんにちは！今日は素晴らしい 機械を使って冒険に出かけます。
into the past. We're going to master something called the simple past tense and trust me it's
過去に遡る旅です。シンプルな過去形を マスターしますが、楽しいですよ。
actually a lot of fun. Let's do this! So let me ask you something. Think about yesterday or maybe
さあ、質問です。昨日や先週末を 思い出してみてください。
last weekend. Did you play an awesome new video game? Binge watch a cool anime? How do you tell
新しいゲームをプレイしましたか？ 面白いアニメを一気見しましたか？
your friends about all that cool stuff in English? You know how do you share the fun things that
それを英語で友達にどう伝えますか？ 楽しい出来事をどう共有しますか？
that have already happened. Well, to tell those awesome stories,
すでに起こったことを話すためには、 特別な力が必要です。
you need a very special power.
タイムトラベラーにならなければなりません。
You need to become a time traveler, seriously.
動詞、つまり動作の言葉を過去に 送る必要があります。
You've got to send your verbs, your action words back in time.
今日はそのための鍵をお渡しします。
And today I'm giving you the keys
それが、動詞タイムマシンです。
to the incredible machine that can do just that.
これは公式のユーザーマニュアルです。
That's right, say hello to the verb time machine.
ここが終わる頃には、あなたは過去の 物語を語るマスタータイムトラベラーです。
Think of this as your official user manual.
さあ、最初の過去への旅はとても簡単です。
By the time we're done here,
現在、あなたは「I play tennis」と言います。
you are going to be a master time traveler
でも、昨日はどうでしょう？右を見てください。
ready to tell any story from your past. Okay, so check this out.
「play」の末尾にEDを加えるだけです。
Our first trip to the past is actually super simple.
そうすると、「I played tennis yesterday」となります。
Right now, in the present, you might say, I play tennis.
この小さなEDが、タイムマシンの メインボタンです。
But what about yesterday? Look at the right.
そのメインコントロールにズームインしましょう。
All we did was add ED to the end of play.
これは、全体の機械で押しやすい 大きなボタンです。
So it becomes, I played tennis yesterday.
基本的な停止ボタンです。
That little ED is the main button on our time machine.
これをたくさん使うことになります。
So let's zoom in on that main control.
このボタンはあなたの新しい親友です。
This is like the big, giant, easy to press button
なぜなら、これは規則動詞に 使えるからです。
on the whole machine. It's the basic stopped button.
素晴らしいニュースは、英語の動詞の ほとんどが規則動詞です。
And you're gonna be using this one a lot.
ほとんどのタイムトラベルでは、
Now this button is your new best friend
動詞の末尾にEDを加えるだけで、
because it works on what we call regular verbs.
簡単に過去に行けます。
And the great news is most verbs in English are regular.
さあ、実際に見てみましょう。
So if we're pretty much most of your time traveling,
アメリカの独立記念日のバーベキューを 考えてみてください。
all you have to do is slap an ED on the end of the verb
「He cooked hamburgers」と言えます。 学校の後はどうですか？
and bam, instant time travel. You're in the past, it's that easy.
「She walked to the library」と言えます。 昨夜は「They watched the Super Bowl on TV」と。
Let's see it in action.
見てください、cook、walk、watch。
Think about a classic American 4th of July barbecue.
彼らはEDを加えるだけで過去に 飛び込めました。
You could say, he cooked hamburgers. Or what about after school?
さて、メインパワーボタンは理解できましたね。 気分はどうですか？
She walked to the library.
レベルアップの準備はできましたか？ 次はプロゲーマー向けの特別設定です。
And last night, they watched the Super Bowl on TV.
これは、難しい状況を扱いたい エキスパートタイムトラベラーのためです。
See, cook, walk, watch.
私たちのタイムマシンには、 スペルのための特別な設定が3つあります。
All they needed was that ED to jump into the past.
Eで終わる動詞用、Yで終わる動詞用、 短い動詞用のプロのヒントです。
Okay, you've got the main power button down. Feeling good?
心配しないでください、パターンを見れば とても簡単です。
Ready to level up? Because now we're moving on
さて、設定1です。これは常識です。
to the pro-gamers special settings.
動詞がすでにEで終わる場合、 例えば「like」や「use」など、
This is for all you expert time travelers out there
もう一つEを加える必要はありませんよね？ それはおかしいです。
who wanna handle the trickier situations.
だから、Dを加えるだけです。それだけです。
So our time machine has three special settings for spelling.
「like」は「liked」になり、「use」は「used」になります。 とても効率的です。
We've got one for verbs that already end in E,
次にYで終わる動詞についてです。 これは2つの異なるパターンがあります。
another for verbs that end in the letter Y,
それはYの前の文字によります。
and a final pro tip for short verbs like stop.
もし子音なら、例えば「study」のDのように、 少し変更します。
Don't worry, they're super easy once you see the pattern.
YをIに変えてEDを加えます。 「study」は「studied」になります。
All right, setting number one. This one is just common sense, really.
でも、Yの前が母音の場合、 つまりAEIOUのように、
If a verb already ends in the letter E, like the words like or use,
「play」のAのように、普通の方法で EDを加えます。
Play becomes played. And here it is, our final pro tip.
「play」は「played」になります。これが最後のプロのヒントです。
This is for those short little verbs like stop or plan.
これは「stop」や「plan」のような短い動詞についてです。
See that pattern? Consonant, vowel, consonant, S-T-O-P.
このパターンが見えますか？子音、母音、子音、S-T-O-P。
When you see that pattern,
このパターンを見たら、
you double the last letter before adding E-D.
最後の文字を重ねてからE-Dを加えます。
So stop becomes stopped with two P's.
だから「stop」は「stopped」になります。
It's a small trick, but it's what makes it sound right.
小さなコツですが、これが正しい音にします。
Okay, you've mastered the main button.
さて、メインのボタンはマスターしました。
You've unlocked the pro gamer settings.
プロゲーマー設定が解除されました。
You're feeling pretty confident, right? Well, hold on.
自信がついてきましたね？でも、待ってください。
There's one more part to this time machine.
このタイムマシンにはもう一つの部分があります。
A hidden level, a secret, warp zone.
隠されたレベル、秘密のワープゾーンです。
You see, some verbs, they're just rebels.
実は、一部の動詞は反抗的です。
They don't play by the rules.
ルールに従いません。
They look at that ED button and they're like, nope, not for me.
EDボタンを見ると、「いや、私には関係ない」と言います。
These verbs have their own secret portals to jump into the past.
これらの動詞は、過去に飛ぶための秘密のポータルを持っています。
We call these guys irregular verbs.
これを不規則動詞と呼びます。
Okay, let's open the top secret files. Check these out.
さて、極秘ファイルを開きましょう。これを見てください。
Go doesn't become good, no way.
「go」は「good」にはなりません。
It warps into went, like I went to the movies.
「went」に変わります。映画に行ったという意味です。
Eat completely changes into ate.
「eat」は「ate」に完全に変わります。
She ate a huge slice of New York pizza.
彼女はニューヨークピザの大きなスライスを食べました。
You see, they totally transform.
見てください、彼らは完全に変身します。
You just gotta learn their secret identities.
彼らの秘密のアイデンティティを学ぶだけです。
And there are more, see, become saw.
他にもあります。「become」は「saw」になります。
Get turns into got, like I got a new comic book last week.
「get」は「got」に変わります。先週新しい漫画を手に入れました。
Speak becomes spoke. Yeah, you do have to memorize these,
「speak」は「spoke」になります。これらは覚える必要がありますが、
but think of them like special cheat codes in a video game.
特別なチートコードのように考えてください。
Once you know them, your English level goes way up.
一度知れば、英語のレベルが大幅に上がります。
And just like that, you've done it, training complete.
こうして、あなたは達成しました。トレーニング完了です。
You've explored every button, every special setting,
すべてのボタン、特別な設定、
and every secret portal in the verb time machine.
そして動詞のタイムマシンの秘密のポータルを探りました。
So before I send you off on your first mission,
では、最初のミッションに出発する前に、
let's do a quick final check. So just remember the controls.
簡単な最終チェックをしましょう。コントロールを覚えておいてください。
Your main power is just adding EED.
メインの力はE-Dを加えることです。
Use your pro settings when you see verbs ending in E or Y.
EやYで終わる動詞にはプロ設定を使ってください。
And for those rebel verbs,
そして反抗的な動詞には、
jump into the secret warp zone and use their special forms.
秘密のワープゾーンに飛び込んで特別な形を使います。
You have all the tools you need. So I'm gonna ask you one more time.
必要な道具はすべて揃っています。もう一度聞きます。
What did you do yesterday? What's a great story you can tell?
昨日何をしましたか？素晴らしい話はありますか？
Did you study for a test? Did you go to the park?
テストの勉強をしましたか？公園に行きましたか？
Did you see a friend? Now you can actually say it.
友達に会いましたか？今、実際に言えます。
You are now a fully licensed time traveler.
あなたは今、完全にライセンスを持ったタイムトラベラーです。
You have the power to share your past and tell your stories.
過去を共有し、物語を語る力を持っています。
So go on, your first mission starts now. Good luck out there.
さあ、あなたの最初のミッションが始まります。頑張ってください。